Diaz Linggaputra

Full-Stack Developer

Jakarta, Indonesia (+62) 812-8307-1034 diazlinggaputra@gmail.com github.com/diazlp linkedin/diazlinggaputra

An adept JavaScript programmer excelling in the environment stack, specializing in front-end development with a very strong grasp of full-stack development. I do my work fueled with passion and curiosity and always try to deliver with the highest quality. Actively taking initiative and demonstrating genuine care for my work.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tomei Consolidated Bhd, Kuala Lumpur - *Full-stack Developer (Remote)*

JUL 2022 - PRESENT

Tomei Consolidated Berhad is a leading jewelry brand in Malaysia, I am responsible for developing both internal facing and external facing interface for numerous projects. I am/have:

- Collaborating with Project Managers and Tech Leaders to build multiple applications using a versatile JavaScript Stack
- Developing multiple applications as a full-stack developer using React, NextJS, React
 Native, NestJS, ExpressJS, as well as Socket.IO, Prisma, Sequelize
- Facilitating merge and/or pull requests while deploying them to Microsoft Azure SaaS and On-premise servers
- Resolving issues and applying hotfixes to align with technical specifications and uphold software quality standards
- Developed an internal-facing application that is currently in use by dozens of store outlets throughout Malaysia
- Developed an external-facing application that is currently in use by hundreds of Tomei customers

SanberCode, Remote - Assistant Trainer

FEB 2022 - APR 2022

- Collaborated with the lead trainer to deliver engaging and effective learning experiences for Data Science Programs
- Facilitated group counseling sessions to help students maximize their learning potential and achieve their academic goals

 Evaluated student performance on a daily basis, including their completion of daily tasks, weekly quizzes, and monthly project assignments, providing feedback and support as needed

PKS Digital School, Remote - Assistant Trainer

OCT 2021 - DEC 2021

- Collaborated with the lead trainer to deliver engaging and effective learning experiences for Data Science Programs
- Facilitated group counseling sessions to help students maximize their learning potential and achieve their academic goals
- Evaluated student performance on a daily basis, including their completion of daily tasks, weekly quizzes, and monthly project assignments, providing feedback and support as needed

EDUCATION

Hacktiv8 Indonesia - Full Stack Javascript Graduates

FEB 2022 - APR 2022

Final Score: 96.0%

Graduation Status: Teacher's Awards

Bandung Institute of Technology - Bachelor of Science, Astronomy

AUG 2015 - DEC 2021

Thesis: Analysis of The Effect of Overshooting to The Evolution of Intermediate Mass Stars

SKILLS

Frontend: ReactJS, NextJS, React Native, Redux, Vue, Pinia, MaterialUI, SemanticUI, DaisyUI, Ant Design, Tailwind, Bootstrap, NativeBase, jQuery, Font Awesome 5

Backend: Express, Node.js, Sequelize, Adonis.js, Firebase, MongoDB, mongoose, Apollo, GraphQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, NestJS

Utilities: Git, TypeScript, Docker, axios, json-server, Jest, Supertest, Midtrans, Sendgrid Mail API, Socket.io, bcryptjs, JWT, Redis, js-cookie, Google OAuth, Stripe API, Expo, simple-peer, Ciprand API, Nginx

CERTIFICATION & COURSES

Golang Backend Development - SanberCode

DEC 2023 - JAN 2024

DevOps - SanberCode

NOV 2023 - DEC 2023

Intro to Product Management - RevoU

OKT 2023 - NOV 2023

Next JS - SanberCode

OKT 2022 - NOV 2022

Node JS Backend Development with Adonis - SanberCode

FEB 2022 - MAR 2022

Advance Python Data Science: Public Interest Analysis - SanberCode

JAN 2021 - FEB 2021

React JS Web Frontend - SanberCode

DEC 2021 - JAN 2021

Agile Development using Scrum Framework - SanberCode

FEB 2021 - MAR 2021

Laravel Web Development - SanberCode

JAN 2021 - FEB 2021

Python: Data Science - SanberCode

DEC 2020 - JAN 2021

PROJECTS

RanChat - Random Video Chat App

MAY 2022

Role: Team Lead, Full-stack

In this project, my project management skill was tested. I have to conceive how we would make our ideas come together as a fully working app. I used agile methodology for our workflow with kanban methodology. Our tech stacks consisted (but not limited to): React, Redux, Socket.io, simple-peer, Sequelize as PostgreSQL ORM, MongoDB, Express, and also Multer, Sendgrid API, and Midtrans

Link: https://ranchat-app.web.app/

Travel10 - eCommerce Ticket App

APR 2022

This was, by far, the most dedicated and integrated solo project that I have created on my whole programming journey. **Travel10** also grants me for *Best Individual Project* in Phase 2 of Hacktiv8 RMT22 Batch

Link: https://travel10-7a8bd.firebaseapp.com/

Intermediate Mass Stars Overshooting Effects - Undergraduate Thesis

DEC 2021

If anything, this was once proudest moment to graph big data in Python for my thesis defense, and I'm absolutely still proud of it. Python modules that were used: *Matplotlib, Pandas*, and *mesa_reader*

Link: https://github.com/diazlp/intermediate-mass_stars_overshooting-effects

MooGames - Movie and Games Library App

JAN 2022

This project grants me the best project award on SanberCode - React JS Web Frontend course on that specific course batch. This one is the very first time I spent almost a week coding a simple working app. Tech stacks that were used: React, Redux, Express, and mongoose

Link: https://morning-hollows-84886.herokuapp.com/

ANTM Q1 Sentiment Analysis

FEB 2021

If you've ever wondered how I ended up working in the same place I studied, this project was the answer. This project also grants me the best project on that specific course batch. I studied, cleaned, and processed twitter sentiment for some specific period of time, to analyze how it would affect the stock market with *auto_arima* modeling. Python modules that were used: *Matplotlib, Seaborn, Numpy, Pandas, BeautifulSoup, yfinance, newspaper, NLTK, Sastrawi, PIL, and WordCloud*

Link: https://github.com/diazlp/Sentiment Analysis-ANTM g1 2021

Nitya - Cattle Feed Co.

FEB 2022

This small project was the first time I received payment to build a simple landing page. No tech stack were used except HTML, CSS, and vanilla JavaScript

Link: https://nitya-landing-page.netlify.app

Other Projects

Halo, Dek - Telemedicine App

Link: https://halodekapp.herokuapp.com/

Ikiwae - Furniture eCommerce App

Link: https://ikiwae-app.netlify.app/

Moogames-V2 - Movie and Games Library App

Link: https://moogames-v2.firebaseapp.com/

Moogames-V2 Mobile - Movie and Games Library App (React Native with Expo)

Link: https://expo.dev/@diazlp/moogames-v2-rn